

# **ZAKARIA AMCHICH**

**Address:** CASABLANCA **Phone:** (+212) 696462071

Email: zakaria.amchich1@gmail.com

Website: zakariaamchich.me

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack developer and Junior Data Scientist with a B.Sc. in Computer Science. Strong background in MERN stack, and Al solutions. Passionate about using technology to solve real-world challenges. Experienced in software development. Founder of CRM Aven and Fhamni Academy.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Software Engineer at Helberton school & Alx

Dec 2022 - Aug 2024

- · Programming Languages: Python, C, Shell Scripting
- Full-Stack Development: Python/Django, React, Front-end/Back-end Integration

### Data Scientist at ALX in partnership with ExploreAl Academy

Sept 2023 - Aug 2024

- Data Analysis: Data Cleaning, Data Wrangling, Statistical Analysis, Power BI
- Machine Learning: Supervised/Unsupervised Learning, Model Evaluation, Python Libraries (Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn)
- Big Data: Working with large datasets, SQL, Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

### BSc Computer Science at FSAC - University Hassan II

Sep 2018 - Jul 2022

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms, Data Structures, Software Engineering, Database Systems,
Web Development, Applied Mathematics

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Founder & Full-Stack Developer CRM Aven

Aug 2024 - Present

Led platform developmentand managed all aspects of CRM Aven

### Al Chat Application ALX Final Project

July 2024 - Aug 2024

- Technologies: MERN Stack, Vite, Clerk, Gemini API
- Built an Al chat application with real-time messaging and image upload features.
- Integrated Gemini's API for NLP, enhancing chatbot interactions.

### Al Image Generator | Academic Project | ALX

April 2024 - May 2024

- Technologies: Python, Hugging Face, Thinker library
- Developed a desktop application for image generation using a pre-trained model.

# Mobile Chat Application | PFE of B.Sc. in Computer Science

Feb 2022 - July 2022

- Technologies: Flutter, WebSocket.io
- Built a real-time messaging app wi cross-platform support.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, JavaScript, Shell Scripting, Php
- Frontend: React.js, Vite, HTML5, CSS3, Flutter
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Django, Laravel
- · Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Al & Data Science: TensorFlow, Hugging Face, Pandas, Scikit-learn
- Tools & DevOps: Git, Docker, WebSocket.io

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Programming Foundations (Duke University)
- Digital Marketing (São Paulo)
- · Languages: English, French, Arabic